クン ク～ン
ひいっ
ううっ うあああ…
あと20分 あと20分…
Twenty more minutes...
あと20分 あと20分 あと20分…
I liked dark, cramped spaces,
so I'd bury my face deep in my hood
My eyes resented the heartless world,
but yearned for love
I liked being soaked by the rain,
because my face looked better clouded over
I pretended to be afraid of the storm
while waiting for the sky to burst
Strum through the light's distortion
I want to make thunder roar
Drum beyond the pain
What can I do? This fierce
pounding is out of control
Strum in a harmonizing quartet
I want to cause a revolution
Drum in a lamenting forte
What can I do? My savage
nature is beyond wild
BOCCHI THE ROCK!
#02 See You Tomorrow
Several Days Earlier
Yesterday, Nijika-chan said...
昨日 虹夏ちゃんから…
Hi there!
Thanks for
everything today!
You seriously
saved our butts,
Bocchi-chan
Nijika
Hello thank you
GRATITUDE
Let's have a talk about our
future as a band! Meetup
at Starry tomorrow, okay?
Hi there!
Thanks for
everything today!
You seriously
saved our butts,
Bocchi-chan
Nijika
You seriously
saved our butts,
Bocchi-chan
Nijika
Let's have a talk about our future as a band!
今後のバンド活動について
みんなで話し合おう！
Meetup at Starry tomorrow, okay?
明日 STARRY集合ね！
と…
家族以外からのLOINEに浮かれて
The joy of getting LOINE messages
from someone who wasn't a relative
やって来たのは いいものの
got me this far, but...
If I walk in there looking
like the hick I am,
こんな芋娘が入ったら
“なんだ？　こいつ”的な目で
見られるだろうし
they'll all look at me
like I don't belong there...
I made it in last time because
I was with Nijika-chan, but...
前は虹夏ちゃんと一緒だったから
入れたけど
I wonder if anyone's there?
誰か入らないかな…
I wish I had someone to go in with.
誰かと一緒に入りたい
Five minutes.
５分　あと５分たったら
絶対入ろう
I'll wait five minutes, then go in.
No, ten...
いや 10分…
Fifteen.
15分　15分たったら絶対
I'll totally go in after fifteen.
What's she doing?
何してるんだろう？
Bo—
ぼっ…
待って
Wait.
I wanna watch a little longer.
もうちょっと見てたい
Could you please stop enjoying this?
鑑賞するの やめたげて
あっ
はい！
Okay!
I hereby declare the first Kessoku Band
members' meeting... open!
ということで 第１回
結束バンド メンバーミーティング
開催しま～す
Round of applause!
拍手！　パチパチ パチパチ
パチパチ パチパチ～
Clappy clappy clap clap clap!
Now, let's see...
それじゃあ ええっと…
Oh, wait. We barely know each other,
so I dunno what to talk about!
思えば 全然 仲良くないから
何話せばいいか分かんないや
She just admitted it!
身も蓋もない！
あっ
そんなときのために
こんなものを
I brought this for just such an occasion.
Bungee Jumping
Nice one!
いいね～
I don't think I like the looks of this...
なんか ヤバそうなもの
混ざってるけど…
はい　何が出るかな♪
There!
What'll she roll? What'll she roll?
何が出るかな♪
Dun-dun-dun-dun-dun...
デデデンデン デデデン デンデン♪
Talk about School
Talk about school!
学校の話！　略してガコバナ～
TAS for short!
Talk about School
はい どうぞ
ええ～？
Proceed.
Do not spill drinks! You may be liable for damages caused.
Um... Wait, don't you both
go to the same school...
ええと… ああ そういえば
Talk about School
２人とも同じ学校…
Yeah, Shima High!
そう 下高
２人とも家が近いから選んだ
We chose it 'cause it's close to home.
Oh, so you live in Shimo-Kitazawa...
あっ 下北沢にお住まいで
Huh? Bocchi-chan, don't you go to Shuka High?
あれ？
ぼっちちゃん 秀華高でしょ？
家 ここら辺じゃないの？
Shouldn't you live around here too?
あっ いや 県外で片道２時間です
No, I live out-of-prefecture.
Two-hour commute each way.
Two hours?!
えっ なんで？
２時間
Why?
I wanted a high school
where nobody knew my past.
高校は
誰も自分の過去を
知らない所に
行きたくて…
Okay, enough TAS!
はい ガコバナ終了～
S-Sorry...
す… すみません
高校でも基本 一人なもので
I spend most of my time at school alone,
その 楽しい浮かれた お話ひとつも
提供で… できなくて
so I don't have any f-fun
stories to contribute...
Hey, it's okay!
大丈夫 大丈夫
Ryo doesn't have many friends either.
リョ… リョウもね
そんな友達いないし
うん　虹夏だけ
Yeah, just Nijika.
Tha-thump.
えっ？
ドクン…
Ryo-san is just like me...
リョウさんは私と同類なんだ
Loneliness Hill
休みの日は 一人で廃墟探索したり
On days off, she does urban exploration
and visits second-hand clothing shops...
古着屋さん回ったり
No, she's not...
いや 違う！
Ryo-san likes being alone!
リョウさんは
“一人でいるのが好きな人”だ！
うっ ああっ
Someone with social anxiety could never
enter a clothing shop on her own!
コミュ症は 一人で服屋入れないし
Lonely
The gap between the lonely and the loner
is too deep and vast to ever be traversed!
“ぼっち”と“一人好き”の間には
Loner
決して埋めることのできない
深く大きな溝が！
危うくトラップに
引っ掛かるところだった
I nearly fell into the trap.
Bocchi-chan, let's enjoy the conversation!
ぼっちちゃん
会話を楽しもうよ
Talk about Favorite Music
Next up, we'll talk about our favorite music!
次は 好きな音楽の話～
For short...
略して…
オトバナ～
TAFM!
オ… オトバナ～
T-TAFM...
I like Japanese punk, like mellow core.
あたしはね メロコアとか
いわゆるジャパニーズパンクかな
I like techno kayo,
私はテクノ歌謡とか
and lately I've been checking
the Saudi Arabian charts—
最近は サウジアラビアの
ヒットチャートを…
True stuff only, please!
そこ ウソつかない～
That is true.
ホントだもん
ぼっちちゃんは？
Bocchi-chan?
あっ その…
Oh, um...
I like any songs that don't
trigger my seishun complex.
青春コンプレックスを
刺激する歌以外なら なんでも
ん？　青春コンプレックス？
"Seishun complex"?
Allow me to explain!
説明しよう！
Guitar Man's Easy-to-Learn Hitori Classes
Seishun Complex Edition
Songs that trigger Hitori's seishun complex
青春コンプレックスを
刺激する歌とは
Guitar Man's Easy-to-Learn Hitori Classes
Seishun Complex Edition
are glitter-coated upbeat songs
that include words like
夏とか青い海 花火 淡い恋といった
"summer," "blue sea,"
"fireworks," "puppy love,"
ひとりの学校生活には
無縁のワードが多用されて
and other things irrelevant to
her personal school experience!
キラキラにコーティングされた
爽やかな歌のことである
Such words plunge me into a deep melancholy.
そういう歌詞聞くと
鬱々としてくる…
Hey, Bocchi-chan?
By the same token,
逆に青春時代の鬱憤を
ぼっちちゃん？
you love bands that write about the
bleakness of their high school years, right?
歌詞に
たたきつけているバンドは
大好物だよね？
Hey...
Oh, yeah!
うん うん
But sometimes I find out a band I love
was super popular in school,
けど 好きなバンドが
学生時代から人気者なんて知ったら
and they suddenly feel
like strangers to me...
急に遠い存在に
思えちゃったりして
Hey, please! Come back to our planet, please!
お～い おねが～い
一人の世界に入らないで～
Rock resonates as the music
of the perpetual underdog.
ロックとは 負け犬が歌うから
心に響くのであって
成功者が歌えば…
Is it really rock if it's
sung by life's winners?
お～い！
もうロックとは言わない
I'm trying to establish some ties, here!
みんな結束してよ～！
Since we're named after zip ties.
結束バンドだけに
Talk about the Concert
Um...
え～と
Our first concert was instrumentals only,
初ライブはインストだったけど
次はボーカル入れたいんだ
but I'd like to have vocals next time.
あっ そうなんですか
Oh, do you?
The guitarist who ran off was
gonna be our singer, but...
ホントは 逃げたギターの子が
歌うはずだったんだけど
あの子 どこ行ったんだろ
Where'd she even go, anyway?
The runaway guitarist...
逃げたギターの子…
Maybe she's socially anxious like me.
私と同じコミュ症だったのかな
No, there's no way!
いや 違う！
If you're really socially anxious,
you can't even run away!
真のコミュ症は
逃げることもできない！
We've gotta find a new vocalist.
ボーカル また探さなきゃ
I can't sing for squat, myself.
あたしは歌 下手だし
Bocchi-chan, can you—
あっ ぼっちちゃんは…
って… アハハッ　だよね？
Yeah... Figured.
Um... Wh-What about Ryo-san?
あっ あの リョウさんは？
あ…
Sob
If I were to serve as frontman,
フロントマンまでしたら
私のワンマンになって
Sob
I'd overwhelm the band and crush it.
バンドを潰してしまう
Sob
Where do you get that
wellspring of confidence?
その湧き出る自信は何？
Sob
羨ましい
その自信 分けてほしい
I'm so jealous.
I'd like a little of that
confidence for myself...
I know!
そうだ！
あっ…
Let's find a vocalist and write a song!
ボーカル見つけたら 曲も作ろうよ
リョウ 作曲できるし
Ryo can write the music,
and if you've got off-limits words,
Bocchi-chan, you should write the lyrics!
歌詞に禁句が多いなら
ぼっちちゃんが書けばいいよ
えっ！　私？
Me?!
Well? Great idea, huh?
どう？　名案じゃない？
The nine years of lunch breaks
I spent in school libraries...
小中９年間 休み時間を
図書室で過ごし続けたのは
Was it all in preparation for this moment?
このための布石？
虹夏は何するの？
あっ…
So, what will you do, Nijika?
えい
Go!
Next, talk about quotas!
次は ノルマの話～
Just shamelessly dodged that one, eh?
堂々と流された
Um... What are quotas?
あっ あの ノルマというのは…
The concert we did yesterday
is called a "booked concert."
昨日出たライブは
ブッキングライブっていうんだけど
バンド側にはライブハウス側から
It's where the club assigns
the band a ticket quota
集客を保証するための
チケットノルマが課せられていて
to make sure enough people come.
Your quota is ten tickets!
ノルマ以上売れた分は
Anything sold over the quota gets
split between the club and the band...
ライブハウスとバンド側で
分け合うんだけど…
ノルマ分 集客できない場合
But if they can't bring in
enough to meet the quota,
その分 自腹で
払わないといけないんだ
the band has to pay the rest out of pocket.
So until you get popular, it's a money pit.
つまり 売れるまで
めちゃくちゃお金いる
ざっくり まとめた！
That's very concise!
A bunch of my friends came
to yesterday's concert,
昨日のライブは
あたしの友達が
結構 来てくれたから
so we managed to meet our quota, but...
チケット はけたんだけど…
あの出来じゃ ２回目は来ない
After that performance,
they likely won't be back.
You said it!
だよね～
リョウは友達いないから
集客 当てにできないし
And Ryo's got no friends,
so she'll be no help...
Bocchi-chan, do you—
ぼっちちゃんは…
Oh, sorry! Forget what I said.
うん ごめん！
大丈夫だから
死んだ魚の目 やめて
Just please lose the dead fish stare!
I've got plenty of imaginary friends, but...
イマジナリーフレンドなら
たくさん いるのにな～
You rock, Hitori-chan!
ひとりちゃん 最高！
Living national treasure!
よっ 人間国宝！
Anyway, since we'll need tens of thousands
of yen before our next concert,
というわけで 当分
ライブのたびに数万円必要だから
ノルマ代 機材代
もろもろ稼ぐためにバイトしよう！
let's get jobs to cover
the quota and equipment!
はい…
Okay.
バイト！
Jobs?!
今日イチ 声出たね
That's the loudest I've ever heard you.
絶対 嫌だ
No.
I don't want to work. Too scary!
働きたくない 怖い　社会が怖い！
Society is too scary!
は？　ブタさん？
A piggy bank?
あっ お… お母さんが
M-My mom was saving up for my wedding...
私の結婚費用に ためてくれてて
これでどうか バイトだけは～
But you can have it.
Just... Please, no job...
あたしたちを鬼にする気？
ありがとう
Don't make us the bad guys here!
Thanks, we'll take good care of—
大事に使わせていただ…
We're not taking it!
いただかない いただかない！
We can't take money that
means that much to you!
そんな大事なお金 使えないから
うっ あっ でも…
But...
I don't wanna work!
働きたくない！　だって…
Because...
うっ… あっ…
いらっしゃいませ
W-Welcome... Sh-Should I warm... up?
あたあたた…
It'd totally be like that...
絶対 こうなって…
Not this cashier who can't even make eye contact lmaoooooooooooooo
うっ… あっ…
いらっしゃいませ
W-Welcome... Sh-Should I warm... up?
あたあたた…
And then that...
こうなって…
Breaking
Defendant Hitori Gotoh's First Trial
For the crime of creeping out the customers,
“お客様に
不快感を与えたで賞”で
we seek the death penalty!
死刑を求刑する！
え～ それでは判決　死刑
Okay, here comes the ruling...
Death!
And then that!
こうなるに決まってる！
…ちゃん ぼっちちゃん
...cchi-chan.
Bocchi-chan.
Bocchi-chan!
ぼっちちゃん！
ふあ
You weren't listening, were you?
今の話 聞いてなかったでしょ
あっ ご… ごめんなさい
え～と なんの話を…
S-Sorry!
Wh-What were you saying?
You should work here with us.
ぼっちも ここでバイトする
ここで…
Here?
へっ？　ええっ！
What?!
You won't have to be scared
if you're with me and Ryo!
Talk about Quotas
あたしもリョウもいるから
怖くないよ
アットホームで
和気あいあいとした職場です
It's a homey and harmonious place to work.
あっ いや…
We can serve drinks, and clean,
and see all kinds of bands!
ドリンクスタッフとか…
Don't wanna work... Don't wanna work...
働きたくない 働きたくない！
Well? What do you think?
ね？　どうかな
う…
Say no, girl!
断れ 自分
Say no!
断れ　断るんだ～！
You have to say no!
I'll dwu mwy bwest...
頑張りましゅ
ホント？　ありがとう！
Really? Thanks so much!
ごめんね 自分
Sorry, girl...
The job'll be more fun if we're all together!
It wouldn't be social anxiety
if we had the courage to say no.
断る勇気があるなら
コミュ症してない
I'll manage the band's funds, then.
それと バンドの経費は
あたしが管理するね
えっ？　あの…
Um... Wouldn't it be better
to have Ryo-san do that?
リョウさんに預けたほうが
いいんじゃ…
What's that supposed to mean?!
どういう意味じゃ！
Listen, Bocchi-chan.
あのね ぼっちちゃん
リョウは こう見えて
めちゃくちゃ お金遣い荒いの
Believe it or not,
Ryo's a very irresponsible spender.
え？
お金持ちで
お小遣い たくさんもらってるけど
Her family's rich and she
gets a huge allowance,
but she blows it all on instruments,
so she's constantly broke!
楽器に つぎ込むから 常に金欠だよ
てれ…
Blush.
What part of that did you
take as a compliment?
どこが褒め言葉に聞こえた？
Anyway, let's work hard
so we can play live again soon!
じゃ 近いうちに
またライブできるように頑張ろう
Then we'll make our major
debut in high school!
そして
高校生でメジャーデビュー！
We start work next week!
バイト 来週からね
学校終わったら うちに直行で
Come straight here after school!
Bocchi. Bye-bye.
ぼっち バイバイ
R-Right...
あっ はい
で…
And that first day of work is tomorrow.
そのバイト初日が
明日に迫っていると
I've been in here for thirty minutes now.
もう30分は浸かってるし
絶対に風邪ひいたよね？
I'm bound to catch a cold, right?
I'm sorry... I'm sorry...
すみません すみません
バイト以外は頑張りますので
I'll work hard at everything except the job.
ハッ！
Mom! Sis is drowning!
お母さ～ん！
お姉ちゃん 沈んでる～
♪ うおぉぉぉ
Catch a cold! Catch a cold!
♪ 風邪ひけ風邪ひけ風邪ひけ
♪ 風邪ひけ風邪ひけ
Catch a cold!
♪ 風邪ひけぇえぇぇぇ!!!
う…
Curse this good health of mine...
丈夫な体が憎い
Then I'll just have to fake—
もう こうなったら いっそ
仮病を…
あっ 虹夏ちゃん
Nijika-chan?
おはよう！
今日はバイト初日だね
Morning!
First day of work, right?
不安だろうけど
ちゃんとフォローするから
I know you're nervous,
but we'll be there for you!
Let's work hard together!
一緒に頑張ろう！
No fair being so nice while
I'm trying to blow off work...
バイトを
バックレようとしている私に
こんな温かい言葉を！
ん？
You've made me realize the
foolish error of my ways.
自分が いかに
愚かなことをしていたか
気付きました
気付かせてくれて
For making an honest woman out of me,
you have my boundless gratitude.
私を まっとうな人間に
してくれて
本当に ありがとうございます
なんの話？
What is she talking about?
I'm here.
着いちゃった
ぼっち頑張れ ぼっち頑張れ
Do it, Bocchi!
Tickets don't go on sale until five o'clock.
チケットの販売は５時からですよ
ひいっ！
We're still getting ready here.
まだ準備中なんで
She works here?!
スタッフさん？
あっ 怪しまれてる
She thinks I'm up to no good...
I've got to clear this up!
誤解を解かないと！
ん～？
あっ 一旦 おちおちおち…
おち… 落ち着いて ててて…
C-C-C-C-C-Calm down...
You're the one who needs to calm down.
そっちが落ち着け
So you're the new part-timer?
新しいバイトの子か
なら 最初から そう言いなよ
You should've just said so.
すすす… すみません
S-S-S-S-Sorry!
あたし ここの店長だから
よろしく
I'm the manager here. Nice to meet you.
よ… よろしくお願いします
V-Very nice to meet you...
The manager's scary.
店長さん ちょっと怖い
苦手なタイプ
I can't handle people like her.
ん？
Nijika-chan, come here quick!
虹夏ちゃん 早く来て～
あれ？
Hey, you're the guitarist
who played in the box.
っていうか
段ボールに入ってライブした
ギターの子じゃん
確か… マンゴー仮面？
Wasn't it... Mango Kamen?
新しい あだ名？
A new nickname?
I like you, Manager!
店長さん 好き！
マママ… マンゴー仮面です
エヘヘヘ
I-I'm Mango Kamen!
That is not her name!
そんな名前じゃないでしょ！
Don't go giving her weird nicknames, Sis!
お姉ちゃんも
適当な あだ名 付けないでよ
おねっ？
虹夏ちゃんのお姉様？
Sis?!
You're Nijika-chan's sister?
前に説明したよ？
I told you before.
When you first came to Starry, remember?
ほら スターリー来るときに
え？
The club we're gonna play at
is called Starry.
今日 出演するライブハウスは
スターリーっていうんだけどね
My big sister's the manager there.
あたしのお姉ちゃんが
そこの店長やってて
っていうか 店の上のマンションに
あたしら家族が住んでて…
Actually, our family lives
in the apartments above it.
ああ
心臓バクバクで聞いてなかった
My heart was pounding so loud
that I didn't hear her.
R-R-R-Really?
そっ そそ… そうでした
That means you don't have to be so nervous.
そういうことなので
だから そんな緊張しないでいいよ
Right, Sis?
ね？　お姉ちゃん
ここでは店長って呼べ
あ…
Call me "Manager" here.
And keep our work and private
relationships separate.
あと 仕事に私情を挟むな
ひっ！
Don't scare her like that!
もう 怖がらせないでよ～
Good Kid
Apple 100
Okaka
じゃあ まずは
テーブルから片そうか
Okay, let's clear the tables first.
それ終わったら拭き掃除を…
When that's done, we'll wipe them all down...
って あれ？　ぼっちちゃんは？
Huh? Where's Bocchi-chan?
あ…
Sorry. I needed a breather
in a dark, cramped place.
すみません 暗くて狭い所で
ひと息つきたくて
ひと息つくの早っ！
You need a breather already?!
じゃあ ぼっちちゃんは
こっちでドリンク覚えよっか
Here, Bocchi-chan, come over
and learn the drinks.
トニックウォーターは ここから
ビールは このサーバーね
Tonic water comes out of here,
and beer comes out of this dispenser.
The cocktails are on the shelf behind...
カクテルは後ろの棚に…
うわあ～
えっ お… 覚えられない
I-I'll never remember it all!
早い！
ちょ… まっ あうあばばば…
Too fast!
I just... mummummmmm...
うっ 歌にして
体に覚え込ませるしかない！
I'll have to infuse the knowledge
into me through song!
うええ～っ どこから出した！
Where did that come from?!
Cocktails are in the rightmost shelf!
♪ カクテルは～
えっ 怖い怖い
You're scaring me!
楽しそうですね
Tequila!
They seem fun.
I'm glad you're learning the drinks,
覚えようとしてくれるのは
うれしいけど
Vodka!
一旦 ギター置こうか
but why don't you set the guitar down?
Kahlua!
Rum!
♪ カルーア！　ラム！
Hey, are you listening?
Weird... She seemed kind of
crappy at the concert, but...
あれ？
前のライブは
下手くそだと思ったけど…
You're not, are you?!
She's good.
You're seriously scaring me!
上手ですね～
ちょっと
怖くなってきちゃったから～
Nijika's trying so hard to stop her,
I don't think she realizes it...
虹夏は止めるのに必死で
気付いてないみたいだけど
P-Please! Come back to us!
Hitori-chan!
But I recognize that sound from somewhere.
この演奏の感じ どっかで…
Hitori-chan!
あっ！
Get to work!
仕事しろ
アイテッ
なんで あたし？
Why me?!
For drink service, just pour the
drinks they order and hand them over.
ドリンクスタッフは
注文されたドリンク注いで
渡すだけだから
は… はい
R-Right...
They can pay 500 yen
on top of the ticket price
チケット代金と別に
500円払うともらえる…
to get a drink ticket.
これがドリンクチケットね
500 yen per drink?
１杯500円って…
And why a drink ticket system?
そもそも なんで
ワンドリンク制なんだろ
Stop staring like it's totally alien to you.
そんな あからさまに
ボッてるみたいな顔しないで
Clubs like this are actually
considered restaurants.
実はライブハウスは
一応 飲食店扱いなんだよ
え？
I don't know all the details,
よく分かんないけど
ライブできる場所ってだけで
営業許可 取るのって
but apparently it's super hard to get a
business license to run just a concert venue.
すごく難しいんだって
な… なるほど
I... I see!
だからドリンクを提供して
So we offer drinks
and operate like a restaurant.
あくまで飲食店として
お店 開くんだって
あ…
Are you listening?
って 聞いてる？
W-Working at a restaurant is advanced stuff!
いっ… いつの間にか
ハードルの高い
飲食店バイトデビューまで
果たしていたとは！
I can't believe I cleared that bar so soon!
Is this... personal growth?!
Loneliness Hill
私 成長してる？
あっ いつの間にか
お客さん入ってきたね～
Hey, customers already!
We're about to be busy, Bocchi-chan!
Loneliness Hill
ぼっちちゃん 今から忙しくなるよ
What?
え？
Wait... Customer service already?!
えっ？　いきなり接客開始？
What do I say?!
なんて言えばいいの？
本日は お日柄も良く
ご来店いただき…
"Thank you for your royal parentage..."
って違う！
せ… せめて１回 予行練習を
That's not it!
J-Just give me a practice run, please!
えっ あっ やっ
ちょ… 待って　待って！
N-No, wait! Stop it!
Thanks for coming!
フウ～
She closed up!
終了しちゃった！
Excuse me! One cola, please!
すみません コーラください
Coming!
は～い　ぼっちちゃん コーラ
Bocchi-chan, cola!
Coming up!
あっ はい
私 ジンジャーエール
I'll have a ginger ale.
Coming up!
Bocchi-chan, show some
respect for the customers!
ぼっちちゃん
お客さんに失礼でしょ！
こここ… 心の準備が！
B-B-But I'm not ready!
We're losing the club's inherent darkness.
ライブハウスの
ダークな雰囲気が失われていく
One oolong and one highball!
ウーロン茶とハイボールで～す
Where's the bathroom?
お手洗いって…
あっ 右奥進んでもらって 左です
Down the hall to your right,
door on the left!
結局
何も成長などしていなかった
I experienced no personal growth whatsoever.
ぼっちちゃん 見て見て
Bocchi-chan, look!
あっ？
Here they are!
Hey, there! We're Alexandism!
え～ どうも！
アレキサンディズムです
Our second album goes on sale today,
They're pretty good, y'know?
あのバンド 結構いいんだよね～
so we're back to doing concerts,
It's a good time to relax.
力抜いて大丈夫
ライブ始まったら暇になるから
but we hope you all bought it!
Once the performances start,
we'll have time to kill.
Thanks!
あ…
Right...
Good work.
お疲れ
お疲れ～　あれ 受付は？
Good work!
We tried to make every single
song better than our first album,
Don't you have to sell tickets?
Manager stepped in for me.
店長が代わってくれた
All of today's bands are really popular,
and if you haven't bought it yet,
we're about to play some of those songs,
今日のバンドは どれも人気あるし
so she told me to watch and learn.
勉強になるから見とけって
That's my sister for you.
so if you like them, please buy the album!
うちのお姉ちゃん あれなの
She's a tsun-tsun-tsun-tsun-tsun-tsun-tsun...
ツンツン…
And there's something I want
to tell you guys first.
ツンツン ツンツン ツンツンツン…
デレ～ みたいな？
...dere. You know?
Excessive tsun.
The crowd rocked pretty
hard at our last concert!
ツン多い
テヘッ
すす… すみません
戦力にならないどころか
S-S-Sorry...
Not only did I fail to help you,
So after it was over, a guy came up
and offered up his card.
お客さんと目も合わせられなくて
I couldn't even make eye
contact with the customers.
Want this?
And we were so nervous. "Is this time
for our major debut?" we thought.
これ使う？　マンゴーじゃないけど
Sorry it's not for mangos.
No, thank you.
使わない 使わない
But it would look pretty lame to let it show,
ハア～
大丈夫！
You're doing fine!
so after a beat we just said,
"Hello, welcome."
今日は初日なんだし
すぐ慣れるって
It's your first day. You'll get used to it!
"Welcome?"
Habits can be scary, huh?
Wh-Why are you so nice to a
sub-water-flea like me?
わ… 私みたいな
ミジンコ以下に
The words that came out of my mouth
どうして そんな優しく
してくれるんですか？
were the words I've said a million
times at my part time job.
フッ
You know...
あたしね…
あっ
このライブハウスが好きなの
According to the guy who gave us his card,
I really like this club.
he wanted to listen to the band
on after us today, Tidaman,
But here and reception are the only places
club staff interact with the customers,
だから ライブハウスの
スタッフさんが
お客さんと関わるのって
ここと受付くらいだし
いい箱だったって思ってもらいたい
って気持ちが いつもあって
but we don't get along with them,
and we really wanna outshine them,
so I want to do my best to make
other people like it, too.
so we hope you listen to Alexandism too!
I'm s-s-sorry.
すすす… すみません
そんな場所でド下手な接客を…
I w-worked so badly at a place
that means so much to you...
いや ちが…
No, no.
Now, let me introduce the band!
That's not what I meant.
そうじゃなくて
あたし ぼっちちゃんにも
いい箱だったって思ってほしいんだ
Always eating curry before a concert, with his
own way of doing things... on bass, Matsuda!
I meant I want you to like
this club too, Bocchi-chan.
And the normal guy who always
has our backs... on drums, Rei!
あ…
I want us to have fun working,
楽しくバイトして
楽しくバンドしたいの
and to have fun playing.
He's got so many effects pedals he barely has
room on stage to stand... on guitar, Koichi!
一緒に
Together.
あっ あ…
まっ いつかは
And on guitar and vocals, without
much to recommend him... me!
'Course, I also hope you'll be able to speak
to customers with a smile some day, too...
笑顔で接客できるように
なってほしいのもあるけど
Tsuyoshi!
じゃ いくぜ！
Let's do this!
あっ ぼっちちゃん 始まるよ！
It's starting, Bocchi-chan!
会場が一体になって
お客さんも演者も楽しそう
The whole place is united.
The customers and the performers
are all enjoying themselves.
Meanwhile, at my concert...
それに比べて 私のライブは…
The customers paid 2,000 yen
to see that, didn't they?
お客さんは 2000円も払って
見に来てるんだよね
If I stay the way I am,
そんな人たちに 今の私のままじゃ
I'm gonna give them the same listless
concert next time too, aren't I?
次もグダグダなライブを
するんだろうな
I want to make the effort to change,
even if only gradually,
少しずつでも変わる努力をして
一緒に楽しくしたい
and enjoy it with the rest of them.
すみません オレンジジュース
Excuse me!
Orange juice.
C-Coming up...
はっ… はい！
あっ
笑顔で お客さんの目を見て接客
Look the customer in the eye. Interact.
Smile!
笑顔で…
Look her in the eye!
お客さんの目を見て接客
Interact!
H-Here you are.
ど… どうぞ～
フッ フフフッ
ぼっちちゃん 目 目！
Bocchi-chan! Your eyes! Your eyes!
ありがとう　ウフフフ
Thanks!
フウ～
Wow, that was nerve-wracking!
いや～ ドキドキした～
でも すごい！
But great job!
You kept your head above the counter
and talked to her!
カウンターから
ちゃんと顔を出して接客できたね
あっ 頑張りました
I did my best!
うん！
Yeah!
ぼっちちゃんのおかげで
Having you here will make my memories
of today's concert even more fun.
きっと今日のライブが
もっと楽しい思い出になったよ
And you've taken a step forward.
ぼっちちゃんも 一歩前進だね
一歩…
A step...
A step.
一歩
A step?!
一歩～？
It feels like I took a thousand, though!
千歩ぐらい
進んだつもりだったんだけど！
う～ん
Tickets go on sale at 5 pm
Good work today.
じゃあ 今日は お疲れ
気をつけて帰れよ
Take care getting home.
バイバイ
あっ お疲れさまでした
Bye-bye.
Th-Thank you for having me.
えっ リョウは帰んないの？
Not leaving, Ryo?
うん もう少ししたら帰る
Staying a little while first.
ぼっちちゃん！
あっ えっ はい
Bocchi-chan!
Y-Yes?!
See you later!
またね
Y-Yes, s-s-s-see you tomorrow!
あっ はい！　ままま… また明日
おっ… 終わった～
It's over!
I made it through an entire day somehow!
なんとか１日乗り切った！
This work thing isn't as hard
as I thought it would be!
バイト 意外と
やっていけそうな気がする
あ… 明日も頑張るぞ～ フフッ
I'll do my best again tomorrow!
Achoo!
ん？
Eh?
Bocchi worked hard, huh?
ぼっち 頑張ってたね
Yeah.
そだね～
それに“また明日”
って言ってくれたね～
And she managed to say "see you tomorrow!"
Yeah.
うん
バンド組めて よかったよね～
I'm glad we formed this band.
Oh, right!
そうだ
ぼっちちゃんにLOINEしとこ
Let's send a LOINE message to Bocchi-chan.
I'll say, "Let's keep it up tomorrow!"
“明日も頑張ろう”って
Nijika
You have a message
う～ん ひどい熱
パパ 氷枕 作ってきて
She's got an awful fever.
Dear, prepare a cold compress, would you?
病院 つれてくか？
Does she need a trip to the hospital?
N-Now I get the fever...
い… 今頃 熱が
Now that we've got Bocchi-chan on board...
ぼっちちゃんも
協力してくれてることだし
あとは…
All that's left...
新しいボーカルを見つけるだけだ！
is to find a new vocalist!
Who's this one for?
これ 誰～？
はいは～い
Me, me! It's me, it's me!
私 私～！　フフッ
The tune that plays when my loneliness
and the pedal are stepped on
Tracks down my cheeks over and over again
The pounding of my loneliness
Is joined by the rhythm of the snare drum
To create a solid pulse
Someone, please remove
the distortion on my heart
And take a look inside me
Nobody can get inside my heart
But it's the kind of night
when I hope someone will
Distortion it's Motion
Once it starts, there's no stopping it
Limits can be overwritten with experience
Isn't that right?
Distortion is always like that
My heart takes off, outpacing my left brain
Toward where you are
An escort to the next note
Distortion on my day-to-day anguish
The chord I play when I'm alone at night
Is it the same for you?
I spent all those days chasing my ideal image
Play an F chord with distortion
So loud that the needle swings off the scale
#3  Be Right There
Watch it!
見てください